easternbank.com 2018-09-27

# Privacy Policy | Eastern Bank

If you wish to print a copy of our privacy policy for your records, please use our printer-friendly version.

Revised: January 2018

Download PDF Privacy Policy  
Download PDF Privacy Policy (en Español)

Why? | 

Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.  
  
---|---  
What? | 

The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include:

  * Social Security number and income
  * Account balances and payment history
  * Credit history and credit scores

---|---  
How? | 

All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the reasons Eastern chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.  
  
---|---  
Reasons we can share your personal information | Does Eastern Share? | Can you limit this sharing?  
---|---|---  
  
**For our everyday business purposes -** such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus

| YES | NO  
  
**For our marketing purposes -** to offer products and services to you

| YES | NO  
  
**For joint marketing with other financial companies**

| YES | NO  
  
**For our affiliates' everyday business purposes -** information about your transactions and experiences

| YES | NO  
  
**For our affiliates' everyday business purposes -** information about your creditworthiness

| YES | YES  
  
**For our affiliates to market to you**

| YES | YES  
  
**For our nonaffiliates to market to you**

| YES | YES  
To limit our sharing | 

  * Call **1-800-EASTERN (327-8376)** —press 3 to speak to a banking representative
  * Visit us online: easternbank.com/privacyoptout

**Please note:**

If you are a _new_ customer, we can begin sharing your information 30 days from the date we sent this notice. When you are _no longer_ our customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice.

However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.  
  
---|---  
Questions? | 

Call 1-800-EASTERN (327-8376)  
  
---|---  
Who we are  
---  
**Who is providing this notice?** | Eastern Bank Corporation ("Eastern")  
What we do  
---  
**How does Eastern protect my personal information?** | 

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.

We will safeguard any information you share with us. In addition, we will limit the collection and use of nonpublic personal information to the minimum required to provide you with superior products or services. We restrict access to your personal account information to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal and state standards to guard your nonpublic personal information.  
  
**How does Eastern collect my personal information?** | 

We collect your personal information, for example, when you

  * Open an account or deposit money
  * Pay your bills or apply for a loan
  * Use your credit or debit card

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus and/or affiliates.  
  
**Why can't I limit all sharing?** | 

Federal law gives you the right to limit only

  * Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes—information about your creditworthiness
  * Affiliates from using your information to market to you
  * Sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing.  
  
**What happens when I limit sharing for an account I hold jointly with someone else?** | An opt-out direction from you will apply to all of the associated account holders for the account numbers you have listed on the Opt Out Form.  
Definitions  
---  
**Affiliates** | 

Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.

  * _Our affiliates include companies with the “Eastern” or “Eastern Bank” name that are under common control with us; nonfinancial companies such as Eastern Insurance Group, LLC, an insurance agency and brokerage firm; and others._

**Nonaffiliates** | 

Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.

  * _Nonaffiliates we share with include government entities in response to subpoenas and other legal processes, credit bureaus, mortgage companies, credit card companies, companies providing servicing, processing, accounting, or similar types of functions, companies originating loans or loan applications, marketing companies, securities brokers, insurance companies, and other financial institutions._

**Joint Marketing** | 

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.

  * _Our joint marketing partners include insurance companies, banks, credit card companies, securities brokers, and financial institutions._

Other important information  
---  
  
Our Policy with Respect to Former Customers: We follow the same privacy policies and practices for former customers as are described in this notice.   
**_Note: If you have already opted-out you do not need to do so again._**
